（香燐）あれ？
あいつ　どこ行った？
Huh? Where'd that guy go?
（サスケ）フン…。
（マダラ）いいか？
（ゼツ）あぁ…。
Ready?
Yeah.
（マダラ）始めろ。
Then begin.
ano suiheisen ga touzakatte iku
Far beyond the horizon it continues
ao sugita sora ni wa ashita sura egake nakute
A sky so blue, you can't draw tomorrow
iki mo dekinai kurai yodonda hito no mure
It's stifling with crowds of people down here
boku wa itsukara koko ni moguri kondan da?
Just when did I dive into this?
kanashimi nante hakidashite mae dake mi tereba iin dakke?
Spit out sadness and keep looking ahead, right?
sore ja totemo matomo de irarenai
You can't stay true to yourself like that
subete o boku ga teki ni mawashite mo
Even if I turn against everything,
hikari o kasuka ni kanji terun da
I still feel glimmers of light
soko made yuke sou nara
If I could only reach it...
iki o shitakute koko wa kurushikute
I want to breathe, I'm suffocating here
yami o miageru dake no boku ja
Only looking up into the dark means,
ukabu houhou mo nai daibaa
I'm a diver who can't surface
iki o shite mite
Take a deep breath
tada no shiawase ni kizuitara mou nidoto oborenai yo
Discover joy, plain and simple and you'll never drown
Painful Decision
《サクラ：綱手様が
意識をとり戻してくだされば→
If only Lady Tsunade would
come out of her coma,
サスケ君のことも
きっと何とかしてくれる…》
I know she would resolve
the situation with Sasuke.
（シズネ）サクラ…。
Sakura...
（サイ）失礼します。
Excuse me.
サイ…。
Sai?
少し　話があります。
I need to speak to you.
ナルトが！？
Naruto did what?!
そう…
サスケをかばうためにね。
Yes.
In order to protect Sasuke.
体中　ボロボロで…。
He was bruised and battered all over.
((カルイ：ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…
こんにゃろ…))
You bastard.
（サイ）でも…
絶対に　サスケを売らなかった。
Still, he refused to sell out Sasuke.
それに…
君を心配させまいと→
Not only that...
In order to prevent you from worrying,
このことは
サクラに黙っておけって…。
he asked me to keep it quiet.
ナルト…。
Naruto...
今は　雷影のもとに→
He's on his way to see the Raikage
サスケのことを許してもらうために
向かったよ。
and ask him to forgive Sasuke.
そんなムチャなこと　どうして！？
Why would he be so reckless?!
カカシさんが　ついていながら…。
Wasn't Kakashi with him?!
おそらく　無理だろうけど…。
It probably wouldn't have
made any difference.
カカシ先生は
ナルトを信じてるから…。
Kakashi Sensei has faith in Naruto.
たとえ　無理だとしても
チャンスは作ってあげたいんだと思う。
Even if it's a long shot,
he probably wants to create
an opportunity for him.
《その場に　綱手様がいても…
同じことを…》
If Lady Tsunade were there,
she'd have done the same thing.
（サイ）サクラ…。
Sakura...
僕は最近　サスケの代わりに→
I was only recently assigned to
Team Kakashi to take Sasuke's place.
カカシ班に配属された。
だから　カカシ班のことは
まだ　よくわからないし…。
So I still don't know
all of you that well.
人の感情も　よくわからない…。
And I'm not good at understanding
a person's feelings.
それに…。
Also...
((ナルト：なっ！？
告白とかしたんですか？
What?!
Did you tell her how you feel?
んなもん　できっかよ…。
How could I?
(約束も守れねえ男がよ))
I'm a guy who couldn't even
keep my promise to her.
君とナルトの約束は知らない。
I don't know the promise made
between you and Naruto.
((ナルト　私の一生のお願い…。
Naruto...
This is a once
in a lifetime request.
(サスケ君を…
サスケ君を連れ戻して…))
Please...
Please bring Sasuke back.
けど　ナルトが君のことを
本当に好きだってことくらい→
But...
Even I can tell that
Naruto loves you!
この僕にだってわかる！
((サクラちゃんは
サスケが大好きだからな。
You care for Sasuke so much.
今　サクラちゃんが
本当に苦しんでるってことは→
And I know what
you're going through right now...
痛いほどわかるってばよ。
so much so that it hurts.
サスケは　ぜってぇ俺が連れて帰る！
I swear I'll bring Sasuke back!
一生の約束だってばよ！
I promise that on my life!
サクラちゃん
約束は絶対　守るってばよ。
Sakura! I'll keep my promise to you.
一生の約束だって
言ったからな　俺ってば。
I swear I'll keep it because I said so.
言ったからな　俺。
I said so...
まっすぐ自分の言葉は曲げねえ。
I never go back on my word.
(それが俺の忍道だからよ！))
That's my Ninja Way.
（シズネ）サクラ。
Sakura...
ナルトは君との約束を
ずっと背負ってるようだった。
It's as though Naruto has
been shouldering
the burden of his promise to you.
一生　背負う気で
いるみたいだった。
As though he intends to bear
that burden for the rest of his life.
君がナルトに
何を言ったのかは知らない。
I don't know what you told Naruto.
でも　それは　まるで
僕のされているものと同じ…。
But it's no different from
what was done to me.
呪印のように感じた。
It's like a Curse Mark.
ナルトを苦しめてるのは
サスケだけど…。
Sasuke is the source of
Naruto's agony.
君もなんじゃないのかい？
But aren't you a part of it too?
（チョウジ）いの…。
Ino...
（キバ）泣くな　いの！
Don't cry, Ino!
（テンテン）キバ！　そんな言い方！
Kiba, don't be so harsh.
いのはね　サスケ君のことを…。
You know how Ino has felt
about Sasuke all these...
しかたねえだろ！
もう昔とは違うんだ。
It can't be helped!
Things have changed since then.
（シノ）大丈夫なのか
いのがこれだ…。
Will they be okay?
Look at Ino.
サクラやナルトは…。
How will Naruto and Sakura take it?
（ネジ）シカマルに任せよう
あいつなら　うまく言ってくれる。
Let's leave it to Shikamaru.
He'll find the right words.
それに　前の小隊長としての
初任務失敗に→
Plus, there was that first mission of his
as a squad leader that failed,
少なからず責任を感じている。
and he still feels somewhat
responsible for it.
あのとき　サスケを奪い返すことが
できていたら…。
If only we had been able to take
Sasuke back that time.
だから　説得役に名乗り出たのさ。
That's why he volunteered
to be the persuader.
（シズネ）待って！　ナルト君は
サクラとの約束だけじゃない。
Wait! Naruto genuinely wants
to rescue Sasuke,
not just because he promised
Sakura! Isn't that so?
自分でサスケ君を助けたいと
心から願ってる！
そうじゃない？
（サイ）もちろんそうだと
僕も思うよ　けど→
I totally agree with you.
But... both Sakura and I...
サクラも僕も
みんなはナルトに頼りすぎてる。
and everyone else rely on
Naruto too much.
最近のナルトを見ていると→
I've watched how Naruto
has been acting lately
感じることが
できるようになったんだ。
and I figured out what he's feeling.
悲しいって。
It's sadness.
そして　サスケのことを考えると→
Then my thoughts turn to Sasuke...
and it starts to get warm inside my gut.
お腹のあたりが熱くなってくる。
それが　怒りなんだって
わかったよ。
I realize now that it's anger.
ナルトのためにも
木ノ葉のためにも→
Whether it's for Naruto's sake
or for the village,
ナルトに頼るんじゃなく→
we can't just rely on Naruto.
僕ら自身が
なんとかしなきゃ駄目だ。
We have to take action ourselves.
サスケは…。
（シカマル）サイの言うとおりだ。
Sasuke is...
Sai is absolutely right.
（シズネ）シカマル君。
Shikamaru...
俺たちは　もうガキじゃねえ。
We're not kids anymore.
俺たちが　暁をとめる。
We must stop the Akatsuki.
そして　サスケをとめるんだ。
And we must stop Sasuke.
俺は　ここに
第七班のメンバーに→
I came here for Team 7's consent.
承諾を得に来た。
まさか　承諾って…。
Consent? Don't tell me...
そう。　それっすよ。
Yes... exactly that.
サスケのせいで　木ノ葉隠れ→
We can't allow war to break out
between the Hidden Leaf
雲隠れが
戦争するわけにはいかねえ。
and the Hidden Cloud
because of Sasuke.
少し遠まわしに話す。
よく聞け。
Let me put it another way.
Listen carefully.
もし　雲隠れが
サスケをやったら→
If the Hidden Cloud should
kill Sasuke,
基本　いのやお前
ナルトが黙ってねえはずだ。
there's no way Ino or you,
or Naruto, would take it quietly.
もし　それでムチャして
いのやお前らが雲にやられたら→
And if through some act
of recklessness,
Ino and you are killed by the Cloud...
俺やチョウジも　いのいちさんや→
neither I, Choji, Inoichi nor
your parents would sit still.
お前の両親だって
黙ってねえし→
仇は　きっちりとる。
They would seek revenge.
そしたら　向こうも
黙ってねえ。　復讐してくる。
Then the other side won't
remain quiet.
They'll want revenge.
それでもし
俺や　チョウジがやられたら→
And if Choji and I are killed,
今度は　俺たちの
親父が出てきて→
then it will be our parents
who take action.
気づけば戦争だ。
And before we know it,
we'll be at war.
雲の伝令役の
情報からして→
According to the messenger
from the Cloud,
サスケは　もう国際的にも
重罪人として扱われる。
Sasuke is already being treated
as a criminal on a national level.
サスケが　これ以上
暁に同調して→
If Sasuke continues to align himself
with the Akatsuki
あちこちで
憎しみを増やしていくなら→
and intensify the hatred throughout
the country,
サスケを木ノ葉の手で
処理するべきと俺は考える。
the Hidden Leaf must deal
with Sasuke.
That is my belief.
俺の言ってる意味
わかるよな？　サクラ。
You understand where
I'm coming from, don't you?
Sakura...
そのための承諾だ。
That's why I need your consent.
サクラ　お前は…。
（サクラ）シカマル。
Sakura, will you...
Shikamaru!
それより先は　何も言わないで。
Please don't...
say anything more.
悪いが　サクラ
お前の答えがどうであれ→
Sorry, Sakura...
But whatever your answer is,
木ノ葉の未来のために
俺は　行動させてもらう。
I must act for the sake of
the Leaf's future.
このことは　ナルトにも話す。
あいつはどこにいる？
I intend to tell Naruto this too.
Where is he?
ナルトは今　鉄の国へ行ったよ。
Naruto has gone to the Land of Iron.
雷影に会うために。
To meet with the Raikage.
あいつ　そこまでして…。
He's willing to go that far?
こりゃ　ひと筋縄じゃ
いきそうにねえな。
I guess this isn't gonna be easy.
ナルトには　私が話をする。
I'll talk to Naruto.
サクラ…。
Sakura!
私なんかを
好きになってくれたバカだから→
He's foolish enough to like
someone like me.
だから　それは
私の役目にさせて。
So let me handle this.
《ナルトをいちばん
苦しめてたのは私だった。
I'm the one who made
Naruto suffer the most.
私は　いつも間違ってばかり。
失敗ばかり。
I'm always messing up.
One failure after another.
もう　間違いたくない。
I don't want to make
any more mistakes.
もう失敗したくない。
I don't want to fail.
だから！》
That's why...
♪～
（エー）
火影を　忍連合の長にするだと！？
Let the Hokage lead
the Allied Shinobi Forces?!
♪～
（ダンゾウ）私でよければ
その任務　請け負うつもりだ。
If you all approve,
I will accept this appointment.
♪～
（エー）なぜ　火影だ！？
Why the Hokage?!
こいつは
忍の闇の代名詞が付く男だぞ！
He is synonymous with
the dark side of ninja!
こんな男に　任せてはおけん！
We cannot let him take charge!
（ミフネ）なら　誰に？
Then whom would you suggest?
我が里から
暁は　１人として出しておらん！
Not one of the Akatsuki came
from my village!
信用を欠いては
その大役は務まらん！
This important post requires trust!
I should be the one to...
その役は　わしが…！
それは　承服しかねる。
なんだと～！？
I cannot agree to that.
What?!
んっ？
強者どもを　まとめるには
それなりの情と→
I am well aware that passion
and strength are essential
力が必要なのは
某にも　わかるが→
in bringing the strong together.
感情任せに　力で行動する
あなたのような方は→
But someone like you,
who lets his emotions rule
his use of power,
連合軍を　その机のように
バラバラにするであろう。
would send the Allied Forces into
disarray like the top of that desk.
中立国から見た　冷静な判断で
提案しているだけでござる。
I am simply making
an objective, rational observation
as a representative of
a neutral nation.
風影殿は　この大権を使うには
まだ若すぎる。
Lord Kazekage is much
too young to wield such power.
他国に　顔がきかぬだろう。
He does not yet have
much pull with nations.
風影の肩書きだけでは　きつい。
His title of Kazekage alone
is inadequate.
土影殿は逆に　歳を召しすぎて→
Lord Tsuchikage, on the other hand,
is too advanced in years
機動力に欠けるイメージがある。
and gives the impression of
one whose power has waned.
それに　暁を利用しすぎた。
And, he used the Akatsuki too much.
信用に　いちばん欠ける。
He is lacking in trust the most.
水影殿は　暁発祥の地とされている
霧隠れだけに→
Lady Mizukage's Hidden Mist is said
to be the birthplace of the Akatsuki.
こちらの情報が
漏れる心配がある。
There is the fear that inside information
will be leaked to them.
スパイがいることも　懸念される。
That there are spies.
暁が　尾獣を集めて
何をするつもりかは知らないが→
We do not know why the Akatsuki
is gathering the Tailed Beasts
or what they intend to do with them.
九尾を　渡すわけにはいかない。
But we cannot let them
have the Nine-Tails.
九尾は　木ノ葉のものだ。
The Nine-Tails belongs
to the Hidden Leaf.
火影が受け持つのが
妥当と考えるが…。
Hence, I believe that the Hokage
is the logical choice.
そもそも　我が里の手の内を
明かすことになる。
First of all, I refuse to recognize
an Allied Shinobi Force
忍連合軍など　わしは認めんぞ！
that would compromise
the security of my village!
《青：何か　釈然としない。
Something about this
just doesn't feel right.
この状況…　確かめてみるか》
I'd better check.
長十郎
戦闘の準備をしておけ。
Chojuro...
（長十郎）えっ！？
Be prepared for battle.
Huh?
《白眼！》
Byakugan!
《こ…　これは…！
Th-This is...
どういうことだ！？
What's the meaning of this?
右肩と　右腕…。
That right shoulder and right arm...
しかも　あの　右目の色は…》
and the color of the right eye...
《間違いない。
There's no mistake.
うちはシスイの色！
It's the color of Shisui Uchiha's eye!
一度　手合わせした強敵。
He was a formidable foe
that I fought against once.
忘れようのない色だ！》
I'll never forget his color!
火影殿！
Lord Hokage!
その包帯の下の右目を
見せていただこう。
I ask that you show us your right eye
underneath that bandage.
（オオノキ）どういうことじゃ？
What's going on?
（青）その右目→
I believe you stole
Shisui Uchiha's eye
うちはシスイの目を奪って
移植したようですな。
and then transplanted it into
your right eye, did you not?
（我愛羅）うちは…　シスイ…。
Shisui... Uchiha?
（メイ）かつての
うちは一族において→
The man praised alongside
Itachi Uchiha
あの　うちはイタチとも並び称された
瞳術の天才か…。
as the Uchiha's most gifted in
the use of the Ocular Jutsu?
ええ。　シスイの瞳術は
相手の脳内に入り→
Yes.
Shisui's particular Ocular Jutsu
allowed him to enter others' minds,
あたかも
己の意思であるかのように→
make them go through phantom
experiences and manipulate them.
疑似体験させ　操る術だった。
操られていることにすら
気づかない。
The victim would be totally unaware
that he was being manipulated.
瞳術でも最高クラス！
It was an Ocular Jutsu of
the highest degree!
火影…　まさか　ミフネを！
Hokage! Don't tell me Mifune
is being...
しかし…　そんな…。
But... that's...
私の右目も　かつての
日向と戦った貴重な戦利品。
My right eye is also
a precious spoil of war,
from a battle against the Hyuga.
あなたと同じで
人のことは言えませんが→
So like you, I am not really one
to talk.
四代目水影にかけられた
幻術を解いた→
But you cannot fool my eye,
この私の目は
ごまかせませんよ！
which undid the genjutsu cast
upon the Fourth Mizukage!
そして　その…。
貴様～！！
And...
Why you!
（ゼツ）ハロー！
Hello!
次から次へと何だ！
One problem after another!
Now what?!
暁か？
Is it the Akatsuki?!
じゃな。
うちはサスケが侵入してるよ！
It seems so.
Sasuke Uchiha has snuck in!
さて　どこに
隠れているんでしょうか？
Now, where could he be hiding?!
なんだと！
What?!
サスケだと？
あいつ…。
なんで　あいつが！
Sasuke?
- Him?
- What's he doing here?!
あの写輪眼の…。
The one with the Sharingan?
白と再不斬をやったやつか。
The one who took down
Haku and Zabuza?
こいつは？
Who's he?
暁のひとり。　確か…。
A member of the Akatsuki.
I believe his name was...
みんなで　サスケを捜してみよう！
オー！
Let's all go and look for Sasuke!
Yeah!
うちはサスケは　どこだ！
Where is Sasuke Uchiha?!
はっきり答えろ！！
Answer me!
《こ…　こいつ
むちゃくちゃ速いな》
Th-This guy is super fast!
答えぬなら　容赦はせん！
If you refuse to answer,
I will show you no mercy!
《サスケ…》
Sasuke...
《お前は　今　どこにいて→
Where are you now?
And what are you thinking?
何を考えているんだ？
俺のことや　サクラちゃんのこと→
Do you think about me, Sakura,
or Kakashi Sensei... even a little?
カカシ先生のこと
少しは考えてくれてんのか？》
《お前は　兄貴のイタチを倒した。
You brought down your
brother Itachi.
復讐をした。　スッとしたのか？
You got your revenge.
Are you relieved?
それとも
もっと苦しくなったのか？》
Or are you in more pain?
《サスケ…　なんで
木ノ葉に帰ってこねえ…》
Sasuke... Why won't you come home
to the Leaf Village?
《憎しみにやられちまったのか？
サスケ！
Has hatred consumed
you completely, Sasuke?
本当に　ただの犯罪者に
なっちまったのか？》
Have you really turned into
a mere criminal?
《今は　お前のことが
わかんなくなってきたってばよ》
Now I'm starting to lose sight
of who you are.
（マダラ）よう。
Hey...
話でもどうだ？　うずまきナルト。
How about we talk,
Naruto Uzumaki?
mayonaka no utaga sakenda
The poetry of midnight cries out,
boku hontou wa ano hi kara zutto
"Ever since that day, I actually..."
akaku sukitooru yuugure no ato
After the twilight in hues of red,
hoshi tachi wa sora ni tsuwari sorezore no oto kanadeteitta
Stars sit on the sky, Each making their own sound
sunao ni nare to iware nakutemo
You don't need to tell me to be true to myself
namida wa mo boku no omoi tsurete
My tears have already taken my feelings
ashi moto de chiisana umi ni natta
and formed a small ocean at my feet
sora wa ugokanai higa nobori oriru dake
The sky is still. Only the sun rises and sets
jimen wa ugokanai kimi ga arukuka arukanaika dake da
The ground is still. It's up to you to take a step or not
mayonaka no uta ga sakenda
The poetry of midnight cries out,
boku hontou wa hitori ga kirai da
"I actually hate being alone. I hate it"
dai kirai da taisetsu wo shitte shimatta ano hi kara zutto
Since that day I learned what was important
aa shiawase nante chiisana spoon de tsukueru kurai de
A small spoonful of happiness is more than enough
jyuubun nanda wakeaeru hito ga iruka inaika dake da
It's just whether you have someone to share it with or not
Next Episode
This is bad.
What is it, Karin?
The Samurai's movements have suddenly become flurried.
もしもし　そこのあなた。
I think they're looking for us!
たまには　空から日本を眺めてみる
というのはどうじゃろう？
What?! But we didn't do anything to be spotted.
今回は東京の有名私鉄スペシャルじゃ。
Must be the doing of that guy Zetsu, who disappeared.
２本も見られる。
That bastard... I'll get him for this.
もちろん　不思議な景色も
たくさん見られるぞ。
There's too many of them! They'll find us in no time.
何ですか　これ！？
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Racing Lightning"
くもみ　こっちもすごいぞ。
Racing Lightning
I'm very irritated
right now.
わぁ！
まったく意味がわかりません。
では　そろそろ出発じゃ。